<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="index-template.xslt" ?>
<index>
	<allnews>
	<news title="Zekr 0.6.0 released!" date="5-8-2007" icon="news.png">
	Zekr 0.6.0 final version is available for download. This is the result of hundreds of hours of mutual development and contributions of both users and developers.<br />
	Here is number of new features over 0.5.0 release:
	<ul>
	<li>Advanced search using Lucene full-text search library (Boolean operators, groups, wild cards, scopes, fuzzy search, ...).</li>
	<li>Uthman Taha theme featuring excellent me_quran font designed by Meor Ridzuan.</li>
	<li>Two versions of Quran text: detailed and simplified.</li>
	<li>HTML export for bookmark sets. A new button is added to "Manage Bookmark Sets" form to export any bookmark set into a single HTML file</li>
	<li>An asymmetric character matching for basic search in order to match Hamza characters better.</li>
	<li>Basic command lines support: -index, -clean, -workspace.</li>
	<li>Two new language packs: Pashto (thanks to Qudratullah) and Bosnian (thanks to Nedim Hadzic and Alma Aganovic)</li>
	</ul>
	This is - I believe - the most bug-free version of Zekr ever released. It looks nice on Debian/Ubuntu Linux as well as Vista (and other defective-by-design systems ;)).
	<br /><br />
	<a href="http://siahe.com/zekr/download.html">Download</a> |
	<a href="http://siahe.com/zekr/wiki/index.php?title=Zekr_0.6.0">Release notes</a>
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.6.0beta2 is available" date="22-7-2007">
	We are happy to announce the new release Zekr 0.6.0beta2. Many bugs are fixed in this release and it introduces the following new features:
	<ul>
	<li>Advanced search now supports fuzzy queries: for example you can search for the term "Allah" and it's 50% similar terms using this query: allah~0.5.</li>
	<li>HTML export for bookmark sets: a new button is added "to Manage Bookmark Sets" form to export any bookmark set into a single HTML file.</li>
	<li>An asymmetric character matching for basic search in order to match Hamza characters better.</li>
	<li>Some command lines added: -index, -clean, -workspace.</li>
	<li>Task pane (the main pane in which you search or choose sura/aya) can be resizeable with the new option added: Resizeable task pane.</li>
	<li>A new language pack: Pashto (thanks to Qudratullah).</li>
	</ul>
	There would be no API change and new feature until final release of Zekr 0.6.0, which will be released by August 1 InshaAllah.
	<br /><br />
	<a href="http://siahe.com/zekr/download.html">Download</a> | <a href="http://siahe.com/zekr/wiki/index.php?title=Zekr_0.6.0_beta_2">Changes</a>
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr Wiki Launched" date="21-6-2007">
	I've installed a wiki (mediawiki) on website, for having Zekr more easily and publicly documented.
	Everyone is invited for contribution. Zekr suffers from lack of documentation, and that's why people
	usually don't use all the facilities it provides.<br />
	This is a multilingual wiki, and you can write/translate articles in your own language.
	<a href="http://siahe.com/zekr/wiki/index.php?title=Template:Languages">Here</a> are some notes.
	<br /><br />
	<a href="http://siahe.com/zekr/wiki">Zekr Wiki</a> |
	<a href="http://siahe.com/zekr/wiki/index.php?title=Wiki_tasks">Wiki tasks</a>
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.6.0 beta 1 released" date="1-5-2007">
	I'm glad to announce a new release the Zekr Project: 0.6.0 beta 1.<br />
	This release is a great step forward, because of it's advanced search feature.
	Here is a brief listing of it's features (over 0.5.0):
	<ul>
	<li>Advanced search using Lucene powerful text search library (Boolean operators, groups, wild cards, scopes, ...).</li>
	<li>A new "Uthman Taha (experimental)" theme is added. This theme uses <a href="http://arabicfonts.wikispaces.com">me_quran font</a> (designed by Meor Ridzuan) for rendering Quran ayas. me_quran font is distributed with the standard package, with permission from it's designer. Windows installer, copies the font into [WINDOWS]/fonts folder; Linux and Mac basic distributions have this font under [zekr]/res/me_quran_volt_mark2.ttf, and one should manually install it in order to utilize a full-feature Uthman Taha theme.</li>
	<li>Detailed Quran text added. Each theme may use the property "quran_detailedTextFile", to use detailed Quran text (a very accurate and detailed text very similar to Uthman Taha's calligraphy) is a property each.</li>
	<li>"sky-vertical" theme is now removed; each theme may show ayas side by side, or line by line  in custom mixed layout (based on the value of the property "trans_showMultipleSideBySide").</li>
	<li>Minor changes: Progress bar in splash screen, JQuery upgraded to 1.1.2, icons enhanced, search configurations are now saved, ...</li>
	</ul>
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.5.0 is Out!" date="12-3-2007" icon="news.png">
	I'm happy to announce the 0.5.0 release of the Zekr project.
	This is mainly a bug-fix release over 0.5.0b2, so you should not expect visible changes between these versions.<br />
	Features in 0.5.0 over 0.4.0 are:
	<ul>
	<li>Bookmark management, supporting multiple bookmark sets, tree-like bookmark folders and items, 
		bookmark set export/import, find aya references to bookmark items, etc.</li>
	<li>A new layout supporting multiple translation at a time: Custom Mixed Layout.</li>
	<li>There are 12 different language packs available with this release.</li>
	<li>A built-in Quran transliteration in English.</li>
	<li>Many small features: random aya, hizb sign, vertical-view-enabled theme for custom mixed layout, etc.</li>
	</ul>
	You can find more details about changes on <a href="changes.txt">changes.txt</a>.<br /><br />
	<img alt="Download Zekr 0.5.0 release" src="img/down16.png"/> Quick download: <br />
		<a href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/zekr/zekr-0.5.0-setup.exe?download"><img alt="Windows" src="img/windows.png" /></a>
		<a href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/zekr/zekr-0.5.0-linux.tar.gz?download"><img alt="Linux" src="img/linux.png" /></a>
		<a href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/zekr/zekr_0.5.0-1_i386.deb?download"><img alt="Ubuntu Linux" src="img/ubuntu.png" /></a>
		<a href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/zekr/zekr-0.5.0-mac.tgz?download"><img alt="Mac" src="img/mac.png" /></a>
	</news>
	<news title="0.5.0 beta 2 Release" date="2-1-07">
	... وَفَدَيْنَاهُ بِذِبْحٍ عَظِيمٍ ..... <br /><br />
	Zekr 0.5.0 beta 2 is out.<br />
	There would be no more feature/functionality change for 0.5.0 release. Here is a short list of the new functionalities in a nutshell:
	<ul>
	<li>Bookmark set group management: add/remove/edit/import/export bookmark sets</li>
	<li>Find aya references within the current bookmark set (a menu item under bookmarks menu)</li>
	<li>Custom mixed layout: multiple translations can be seen in a mixed layout</li>
	<li>Transliteration: there is a built-in transliteration, which is treated as a translation</li>
	<li>New icon for Zekr (Vista compatible)</li>
	<li>Multiple theme/translation import support. Themes and translations can be imported in user home directory (Me-only mode), as well as Zekr installation directory.</li>
	<li>A number of bug fixes</li>
	</ul>
Zekr 0.5.0 will be released as soon as I have language packs updated.<br />
	<img alt="Download Zekr 0.5.0 beta 2 release" src="img/down16.png"/>
	<a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=128414&amp;package_id=144178&amp;release_id=483026">All Downloads</a>
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.5.0 beta 1 is out" date="23-12-06">
	Zekr 0.5.0 beta 1 released.<br />
	There are a number of new features for this release. The main focus of 0.5.0 release 
	is Bookmark support (which is done 90% by this release).
	More features are:
	<ul>
	<li>Printing: instead of just 1 stylesheet, Zekr now uses 2 stylesheets, one for printing and one for screen (monitor) rendering.</li>
	<li>Search: current page search is now more easy to use. One can navigate through search results through buttons on navigation bar.</li>
	<li>Random aya: a new menu item under view menu added to bing you a random aya.</li>
	</ul>
	<img alt="Download Zekr 0.5.0 beta 1 release" src="img/down16.png"/>
	Download it <a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=128414&amp;package_id=144178&amp;release_id=473523">here</a> (Win/Linux/Mac).
	</news>
	<news title="Ubuntu installer package" date="23-12-06">
	An Ubuntu installer package (.deb) is generously contributed by <a href="http://www.iqc.ca/~mderakhshani/">Mohammad Derakhshani</a>.
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.4.0 final release" date="24-10-06">
	Zekr 0.4.0 final release is available.<br />
	This version is the most stable and bug-free release from 0.1.0. There are some new features over Zekr 0.3.0:<br />
	<ul>
	<li>4 new language packs (Dutch, Kurdish, Malay, Turkish)</li>
	<li>Navigation bar for easy navigation through search results as well as different suras/ayas</li>
	<li>Scoped search (search items can be added including or excluding)</li>
	<li>Search through translatios (with unicode match case option)</li>
	<li>Application bundle for Mac</li>
	</ul>
	You can find more details on changes on <a href="relnotes.html">release notes</a>, and <a href="changes.txt">changes.txt</a>.<br /><br />
	<img alt="Download Zekr 0.4.0 release" src="img/down16.png"/> Quick download: <br />
		<a href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/zekr/zekr-0.4.0-setup.exe?download"><img alt="Windows" src="img/windows.png" /></a>
		<a href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/zekr/zekr-0.4.0-linux.tar.gz?download"><img alt="Linux" src="img/linux.png" /></a>
		<a href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/zekr/zekr-0.4.0-mac.tgz?download"><img alt="Mac" src="img/mac.png" /></a>
	</news>

	<news title="Zekr 0.4.0 beta 2 release" date="3-10-06">
	Zekr 0.4.0 beta 2 is available.<br />
	This would be the last beta relase, and God willing, the final 0.4.0 release will be available in 2 weeks.
	The main feature of this release is fully manageable <i>scoped search</i> (through both Quran and translation).
	SWT also updated to a newer one (which should work better on Mac).<br /><br />
	<img alt="Download Zekr 0.4.0 beta 2" src="img/down16.png"/>
	<a href="download.html">Download!</a>
	</news>

	<news title="Zekr 0.4.0 first beta release" date="15-9-06">
	The Zekr 0.4.0 beta 1 is available.<br />
	There are three new language packs (Turkish, Malay, Kurdish) plus a number of visual enhancements.<br /><br />
	Find the new features yourself :)<br />
	<img alt="Download Zekr 0.4.0 beta 1" src="img/down16.png"/>
	<a href="download.html">Download!</a>
	</news>

	<news title="Final 0.3.0 release availability" date="25-5-06">
	The Zekr 0.3.0 final release is now available.<br />
	There are a number of cool features in 
	this release + more stability. The SWT graphics library update to build 3232 and the Russian language pack has been added.
	Also Kuliev's translation is provided with his permission (thanks to Michael Kalinin).<br />
	Please see
	<a href="relnotes.html">release notes</a> page for general features and 
	<a href="changes.txt">changes.txt</a> for more specific changes.<br /><br />
	<img alt="Download Zekr 0.3.0 beta 2" src="img/down16.png"/>
	<a href="download.html">Download!</a>
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.3.0 preview final release is out" date="10-5-06">
	A preview release of the Zekr 0.3.0 is now out. The final release will be available <i>in a week</i>.
	The privew philosophy is that since there is no automated system test for Zekr,
	I can not make sure that there would be no explicit bug.
	Here are the download links:
	<ul>
		<li>
		<a href="http://khorshid.ut.ac.ir/~saboorian/zekr-archive/zekr-0.3.0-preview-setup.exe">
		Zekr 0.3.0 preview release for Win32 (3.41 MB)</a>
		</li>
		<li>
		<a href="http://khorshid.ut.ac.ir/~saboorian/zekr-archive/zekr-0.3.0-preview-linux.tar.bz2">
		Zekr 0.3.0 preview release for Linux (3.39 MB)</a>
		</li>
		<li>
		<a href="http://khorshid.ut.ac.ir/~saboorian/zekr-archive/zekr-0.3.0-preview-mac.tar.bz2">
		Zekr 0.3.0 preview release for Mac (2.94 MB)</a></li>
	</ul>
	</news>
	<news title="Typo in the Zekr Quran text" date="26-4-06">
		There seems to be some fine typos in the Zekr Quran text file.
		<br />
		<ul>
		<li>Al-Nisa(4):90, "أَن يُقَاتِلُونَكُمْ" which should be "أَنْ يُقَاتِلُوكُمْ"</li>
		<li>Al-Hijr(15):3, "فَسَوْفَ يَعْمَلُونَ" which should be "فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ"</li>
		</ul>
		The 0.3.0 will be released with a new Quran text, which is sure more accurate.
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.3.0 beta 2 released!" date="28-3-06">
		Two weeks after the first beta release, the second beta release is out for download.
		<ul><li>
		Different view layouts are now supported, which eases Quran/Translation browsing very much.
		These are <i>Quran-only</i>, <i>Translation-only</i>, <i>Mixed</i> and <i>Separate</i> layouts.
		</li><li>
		Search is more convenient now, since you can see a popup translation for any search result.
		</li><li>
		In both Translaton-only and Mixed layouts, you can search in the view.
		</li><li>
		A simple Options menu is added to set general and theme-related configurations.
		</li>
		</ul>
		This release is successfully tested on JRE 1.4.2 and 5. It also works fine on Linux and Mac.
		A small problem in shell script of the beta 1 release for Mac machines is now fixed.
		<img alt="Download Zekr 0.3.0 beta 2" src="img/down16.png"/>
		<a href="download.html">Download!</a>
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.3.0 beta 1 released!" date="14-3-06">
		The first beta release of the Zekr 0.3.0 is available. This release is maily around two features:
		<ul>
		<li>Theme management: You can change the current theme, or import more themes into the Zekr</li>
		<li>Translation management: you can add a number of different translations to the Zekr</li>
		</ul>
		This release is successfully tested on JRE 1.4.2 and 5.
		<br />
		<img alt="Download Zekr 0.3.0 beta 1"
			src="img/down16.png" /> <a href="download.html">Download!</a>
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.2.0 runs on Mac!" date="24-2-06">
		Zekr 0.2.0 was ported to Mac. Many thanks to Ali Rastegar.
		<br />
		It is tested on Mac OS X Tiger 10.4.5, and JDK 5.0+. Please note that Zekr does not work
		with JRE 1.4.2 on Mac.
		<br />
		<br />
		In order to install Zekr on Mac, please see <a href="faq.html#mac">FAQ (Mac)</a>.<br />
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.2.0 final release" date="26-1-06">
		The 0.2.0 final release of the Zekr project is out!
		<br />
		There is a number of bug-fixes (mainly on search) in adition to some graphical enhancements.
		More easy navigation on search results and a stable Linux port is also done
		for this release.<br />
		Please see <a href="relnotes.html">release notes</a> for more details on this release.
		The next release <b>0.3.0 beta 1</b>, God willling, will available on March.
		<br />
		<br />
		In order to install Zekr on Linux, please see <a href="faq.html#linux">FAQ (Linux)</a>.<br />
		<img alt="Download Zekr 0.2.0" src="img/down16.png" /> 
		<a href="download.html">Download!</a>
	</news>
	</allnews>
	<buttons>
		<button icon="zekr.gif" title="The Zekr Quranic Project" href="http://siahe.com/zekr" />
		<button icon="linux.gif" title="Also works on Linux!" href="http://kernel.org" />
		<button icon="java.gif" title="Written in Java" href="http://java.sun.com" />
		<button icon="apache.gif" title="Uses libraries written by Apache.org" href="http://apache.org" />
		<button icon="sf.gif" title="Hosted on SourceForge.net" href="http://zekr.sf.net" />
		<button icon="ff.gif" title="Get Firefox Now!" href="http://mozilla.com" />
	</buttons>
</index>
