<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="index-template.xslt" ?>
<index>
	<allnews>
	<news title="Final 0.3.0 release availability" date="25-5-06" icon="news.png">
	The Zekr 0.3.0 final release is now available.<br />
	There are a number of cool features in 
	this release + more stability. The SWT graphics library update to build 3232 and the Russian language pack has been added.
	Also Kuliev's translation is provided with his permission (thanks to Michael Kalinin). Please see
	<a href="relnotes.html">release notes</a> page for general features and 
	<a href="changex.txt">changes.txt</a> for more specific changes.
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.3.0 preview final release is out" date="10-5-06">
	A preview release of the Zekr 0.3.0 is now out. The final release will be available <i>in a week</i>.
	The privew philosophy is that since there is no automated system test for Zekr,
	I can not make sure that there would be no explicit bug.
	Here are the download links:
	<ul>
		<li>
		<a href="http://khorshid.ut.ac.ir/~saboorian/zekr-archive/zekr-0.3.0-preview-setup.exe">
		Zekr 0.3.0 preview release for Win32 (3.41 MB)</a>
		</li>
		<li>
		<a href="http://khorshid.ut.ac.ir/~saboorian/zekr-archive/zekr-0.3.0-preview-linux.tar.bz2">
		Zekr 0.3.0 preview release for Linux (3.39 MB)</a>
		</li>
		<li>
		<a href="http://khorshid.ut.ac.ir/~saboorian/zekr-archive/zekr-0.3.0-preview-mac.tar.bz2">
		Zekr 0.3.0 preview release for Mac (2.94 MB)</a></li>
	</ul>
	</news>
	<news title="Typo in the Zekr Quran text" date="26-4-06">
		There seems to be some fine typos in the Zekr Quran text file.
		<br />
		<ul>
		<li>Al-Nisa(4):90, "أَن يُقَاتِلُونَكُمْ" which should be "أَنْ يُقَاتِلُوكُمْ"</li>
		<li>Al-Hijr(15):3, "فَسَوْفَ يَعْمَلُونَ" which should be "فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ"</li>
		</ul>
		The 0.3.0 will be released with a new Quran text, which is sure more accurate.
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.3.0 beta 2 released!" date="28-3-06">
		Two weeks after the first beta release, the second beta release is out for download.
		<ul><li>
		Different view layouts are now supported, which eases Quran/Translation browsing very much.
		These are <i>Quran-only</i>, <i>Translation-only</i>, <i>Mixed</i> and <i>Separate</i> layouts.
		</li><li>
		Search is more convenient now, since you can see a popup translation for any search result.
		</li><li>
		In both Translaton-only and Mixed layouts, you can search in the view.
		</li><li>
		A simple Options menu is added to set general and theme-related configurations.
		</li>
		</ul>
		This release is successfully tested on JRE 1.4.2 and 5. It also works fine on Linux and Mac.
		A small problem in shell script of the beta 1 release for Mac machines is now fixed.
		<img alt="Download Zekr 0.3.0 beta 2" src="img/down16.png"/>
		<a href="download.html">Download!</a>
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.3.0 beta 1 released!" date="14-3-06">
		The first beta release of the Zekr 0.3.0 is available. This release is maily around two features:
		<ul>
		<li>Theme management: You can change the current theme, or import more themes into the Zekr</li>
		<li>Translation management: you can add a number of different translations to the Zekr</li>
		</ul>
		This release is successfully tested on JRE 1.4.2 and 5.
		<br />
		<img alt="Download Zekr 0.3.0 beta 1"
			src="img/down16.png" /> <a href="download.html">Download!</a>
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.2.0 runs on Mac!" date="24-2-06">
		Zekr 0.2.0 was ported to Mac. Many thanks to Ali Rastegar.
		<br />
		It is tested on Mac OS X Tiger 10.4.5, and JDK 5.0+. Please note that Zekr does not work
		with JRE 1.4.2 on Mac.
		<br />
		<br />
		In order to install Zekr on Mac, please see <a href="faq.html#mac">FAQ (Mac)</a>.<br />
	</news>
	<news title="Zekr 0.2.0 final release" date="26-1-06">
		The 0.2.0 final release of the Zekr project is out!
		<br />
		There is a number of bug-fixes (mainly on search) in adition to some graphical enhancements.
		More easy navigation on search results and a stable Linux port is also done
		for this release.<br />
		Please see <a href="relnotes.html">release notes</a> for more details on this release.
		The next release <b>0.3.0 beta 1</b>, God willling, will available on March.
		<br />
		<br />
		In order to install Zekr on Linux, please see <a href="faq.html#linux">FAQ (Linux)</a>.<br />
		<img alt="Download Zekr 0.2.0" src="img/down16.png" /> 
		<a href="download.html">Download!</a>
	
	</news>
	</allnews>
	<buttons>
		<button icon="zekr.gif" title="The Zekr Quranic Project" href="http://siahe.com/zekr" />
		<button icon="linux.gif" title="Also works on Linux!" href="http://kernel.org" />
		<button icon="java.gif" title="Written in Java" href="http://java.sun.com" />
		<button icon="apache.gif" title="Uses libraries written by Apache.org" href="http://apache.org" />
		<button icon="sf.gif" title="Hosted on SourceForge.net" href="http://zekr.sf.net" />
		<button icon="ff.gif" title="Get Firefox Now!" href="http://mozilla.com" />
	</buttons>
</index>

